NEHA NARANG

nehanarang83@gmail.com | +91-09205388157 | +91-09013485612 GitHub Link | LinkedIn Profile | Instagram Profile

Career snapshot

A versatile Information Technology professional with 7+ years in development of web and window-based projects using .Net Framework, C# and Python. Currently working as an Intern in **Artificial Intelligence & Machine Learning techniques.** Work profile spans working solely as well as in teams, supervising and guiding the team, and participating in knowledge transfer sessions.

Technical skills

- AI & Machine Learning Python, Flask, PyCharm, Scikit-Learn, NumPy, SciPy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, keras, Statsmodels, Regression, Classification, Feature Engineering, Clustering, Jupyter Notebook, Power BI and Tableau
- Other skills UiPath tool for Robotic Process Automation, RPA Orchestrator, ASP.Net, C#, Web API, SQL, Git

Employment history

- ➤ Intern in BFS domain, iNeuron, Bengaluru (Jan 2021 till date)
 - Loan Risk Assessment project predicts whether a loan is good or bad. It is built to predict an individual record as well as bulk of records
 - o Enterprise data analysis and statistical analysis
 - o Model building using Random Forest Machine Learning Algorithm
 - Flask API development using PyCharm

> Senior Software Engineer in O&G domain, Sapient/Ameri100, Gurugram (Dec 2017– Sep 2018)

- Truck Ticketing Bot reconciles invoices and validate prices for different counterparties
 - o Bot creation using UiPath
 - o Data extraction from invoices using UiPath and Python
 - Task Scheduler and Orchestrator deployment in staging and production environment
 - o Testing, maintenance and documentation of the project
- GRAM Publish Report Bot extracts data from an application named GRAM, processes extracted values and sends daily emails in a specified format to clients in different locations
 - o Client interaction for requirement gathering
 - Document process automation design, technical document creation, and Bot development, and integration
 - o Test cases design and unit and integration testing
 - o On-going operational support including upgrades, defect fixes
 - Scrum meetings participation
- Data research project involves web scrapping from news portals, creating a json file for each article, saving content in PDF and feeding PDFs to NLP pipeline for semantic analysis
 - o Solely worked on web scrapping from few news sites using UiPath (RPA) and Python
 - o Scheduled Bot on Task Scheduler and Orchestrator
 - o Collected metadata from websites and created json file

> Senior Software Engineer in Travel domain, Make My Trip Pvt. Ltd./FutureSoft Technologies, Gurugram (Dec 2016 – Jun 2017)

- Middleware projects
 - O Developed Windows services and a few stored procedures for sending emails, SMS notifications and reminders to customers on booking tickets using .net framework, C#
 - Developed a web API for sending emails and SMS to customers on flight cancellation and date change request
 - Created test cases and participated in system testing on staging environment
 - Worked on bug fixing and troubleshooting of WCF services, ASP.Net MVC applications (Jira & Jenkins)
 - o Created and updated queries and stored procedures as part of enhancement (SQL server)
 - o Worked under agile methodologies and participated in Daily Scrum Meetings (DSMs)

> Senior Software Engineer in Defense domain, Weapons & Electronics Systems Engineering Establishment (WESEE), Ministry of Defense, Delhi (Feb 2011 – Oct 2014)

- System and Data security projects
 - O Coded for Windows services, Windows form and console applications using .Net framework, C#, VC++, SQL server, Active Directory
 - o Project development, testing and maintenance
 - o Code review, optimization and security
 - o Documentation such as design documents, test cases, project manuals and user manuals

➤ Software Engineer in BFS and O&G domain, Larsen & Toubro Infotech, Mumbai (Jul 2007 – Jun 2010)

- Governance Portal is automation of a dashboard for effective monitoring of Process & Technology, Finance and Control
 - o Requirement gathering, analysis, design, development, implementation and testing
 - o Creation of forms using Microsoft InfoPath
 - o Reports development in SQL Server Report Server and SQL Server
- Onboarding Tracking System to follow onboarding and offboarding activities of employees
 - o Workflow development for onboarding process using SharePoint 2007
 - o Code integration and integration testing
- Enterprise Information Management System
 - o BRD and SRS documents preparation
 - SharePoint site development using MOSS
 - o GUI design customization using Microsoft Office SharePoint Designer
 - o Test plan and test cases development
- Client Engagement Reports (Microsoft Excel, VBA)

Certifications

- Coursera: Machine Learning program
- iNeuron Academy: Certified Machine Learning Masters, Certified Python Developer, Certified in Power BI, Certified in Tableau, 2020
- Microsoft Certified Professional Developing ASP.Net MVC 4 Web Applications, 2016
- NIIT Certified course in Application Development in ASP.net MVC, 2016

Academic credentials

- MCA from Guru Gobind Singh Indraprastha University (GGSIPU), Delhi, 2007
- Bachelor of Information Systems (Hons.) from GGSIPU, Delhi, 2004